<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-04T05:17:35+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Terminal Beach</title><subtitle>Technologies of the screen</subtitle><author><name>Martin Roberts</name></author><entry><title type="html">Algorithms Are Stupid</title><link href="/algorithms/2021/02/19/stupid-algorithms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorithms Are Stupid" /><published>2021-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/algorithms/2021/02/19/stupid-algorithms</id><content type="html" xml:base="/algorithms/2021/02/19/stupid-algorithms.html">&lt;p&gt;What I find most striking about algorithms is not how incredibly smart they are, but how incredibly stupid they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, ever since I looked once at this two-thousand-dollar (reduced to $850!) &lt;a href=&quot;https://insideweather.com/products/el11bt-latte-edgar-lounge-chair-in-butterscotch&quot;&gt;Frank Lloyd Wright easy chair&lt;/a&gt;, it now appears constantly in my feed - and of course will do so even more now that I’ve actually posted about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will appear in yours if you now click on it, having been infected by the Frank Lloyd Wright easy chair virus. If my plan succeeds, eventually everyone’s Facebook feed will consist entirely of Frank Lloyd Wright easy chairs - the algorithmic equivalent of an Ionesco play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The algorithmic reptile brain thinks that because I click on an ad once, or better still even Share it, I must be interested in purchasing it and therefore must be reinforced by being served that ad again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the algorithm doesn’t understand is that every new impression only strengthens my determination never to buy a Frank Lloyd Wright easy chair, even if I had $1,000+ of disposable income to spend on an easy chair (which, God knows, I need at this point), and only increases my hatred of Frank Lloyd Wright easy chairs, and of Frank Lloyd Wright in general, because I now associate both the chair and its architect with this stupid algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://insideweather.com/products/el11bt-latte-edgar-lounge-chair-in-butterscotch&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Martin Roberts</name></author><category term="algorithms" /><summary type="html">What I find most striking about algorithms is not how incredibly smart they are, but how incredibly stupid they are.</summary></entry></feed>